Guide to the United Women Firefighters Records and Photographs WAG.057
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
United Women Firefighters Records and Photographs
Bulk, 1979-1993
1957-2011
WAG.057
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
15.0 linear feet in 14 record cartons, 2 manuscript boxes and one folder.
The United Women Firefighters (UWF) was founded in 1982 as a support organization for women firefighters in the New York City Fire Department. The New York City Fire Department began accepting applications from women for the position of firefighter in 1977, but did not hire any women until after Brenda Berkman successfully sued the City of New York on behalf of herself and other women who had passed the written examination, questioning the validity of the physical exam. The UWF was founded to deal with the occupational and sexual discrimination and the sexual harassment women firefighters faced. These records cover Brenda Berkman's career, legal cases (Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al.; Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al., Appeal; and Brenda Berkman v. City of New York, Carlos Rivera, & Selig Ginsberg), and the founding and development of the United Women Firefighters of New York City and the related national support group, Women in Fire Service (WFS, alternately known as Women in Fire Suppression). The collection contains scrapbook material, personal correspondence, legal documents, organizational files, subject files, clippings, photographs, videos and memorabilia.
Berkman, Brenda
United Women Firefighters.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The original donation of material to the Wagner Labor Archives was made by Brenda Berkman and the United Women Firefighters in 1987. A subsequent donation of four boxes was made by Brenda Berkman in 2002, and additional materials were added by Berkman in 2005 and 2011.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Historical/Biographical Note
The New York City Fire Department (NYCFD, also known as the FDNY by the department) began accepting applications from women for the position of firefighter in 1977, but did not hire any women until after Brenda Berkman successfully sued the City of New York on behalf of herself and other women who had passed the written examination. Berkman, a law student at New York University at the time of her application, sued the City under the 1964 Civil Rights Act, questioning the validity of the physical exam. In 1982, Judge Charles Sifton ruled that the City had indeed discriminated against women through its physical exam, known as the 3040 exam, which included tests that were biased against women and unrelated to a firefighter's future performance on the job. The suit and Sifton's ruling sparked intense controversy in the Fire Department and the media. Litigation related to this original ruling continued until 1988.
The United Women Firefighters (UWF) was founded in 1982 by the first group of New York City women firefighters, in order to deal with the occupational and sexual discrimination, and the sexual harassment, encountered in the Department. Modeled on groups like the Vulcan Society (representing African-American firefighters), the UWF assists women firefighters who have encountered a wide range of problems on the job, from ill-fitting equipment to unjust probation and sexual assault. They have lobbied for training for all officers and firefighters on issues related to women on the job. Representatives of the organization have developed ties with other women firefighters' organizations, including the national coalition, Women in Fire Service. The United Women Firefighters publishes a monthly newsletter, the Voice Alarm.
Brenda Berkman was born in 1951, and became interested in firefighting as a young girl. When she accepted the Susan B. Anthony Award from the National Organization of Women in 1984, she declared that she had become a feminist at age seven, when she was not allowed to play in boys-only Little League. She earned her B.A. from St. Olaf College in Minnesota, an M.A. in History at Indiana University, a J.D. from New York University Law School, and an M.S. in Fire Protection Management from the City University of New York. At the time of her application to the New York Fire Department she was a law student at New York University.
Berkman is a founding member and former president of the United Women Firefighters (1982-1986) and served as trustee of the Women in Fire Service (1983-1992). She taught at the FDNY fire academy and the United States National Fire Academy. Her many awards and honors include the Susan B. Anthony award from the National Organization for Women (1984), a Revson Fellowship on the Future of the City of New York from Columbia University (1987-1988), the distinguished alumni award from St. Olaf College, and the National Organization for Women's Women of Courage Award (2002). For her support of labor history and labor archives, she was honored by the New York Labor History Association in 2005.
Berkman was a featured participant in the PBS program, "Sex, Power, and the Workplace" (1992) and was the subject of the Off-Broadway play, "Firework" (2002). Her story and that of her fellow women firefighters is the focus of the documentary, "Taking the Heat: The First Women Firefighters of New York City" (2006). She was promoted to Captain in 2002, only the third woman to achieve that rank.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of scrapbook material, personal correspondence, legal documents, organizational files, subject files, clippings, memorabilia, photographs and videos from circa 1977 to 2011. The materials document the life and career of Brenda Berkman, the successful legal actions Berkman brought against the City of New York and the New York City Fire Department (Berkman v. the City of New York; Berkman v. NYCFD) between 1977 and 1993, and the unsuccessful appeal by the City of New York to Judge Charles Sifton's 1982 ruling that the City had discriminated against women through its physical exam. The collection also documents the founding and operation of the United Women's Firefighters, and the related national support group, Women in Fire Service.
Arrangement
The records are arranged in five series, two of which have been further arranged in subseries. The contents of each series or subseries are arranged alphabetically, and chronologically within subject when appropriate, with the exception of Series V which consists of unprocesssed materials. The series and subseries arrangement of the records is as follows:
Series I, Brenda Berkman Papers, 1977-2005
Series II, Legal Files, 1979-1993
Subseries A: Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case No. 79, C 1813), Class Action Suit, Legal Documents, 1979-1986
Subseries B: Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case No. 79, C 1813), Class Action Suit, Subject Files, 1979-1990
Subseries C: Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case no. 82-7654), Appeal, 1982
Subseries D: Brenda Berkman v. New York City Fire Department, Carlos Rivera, and Selig Ginsberg, (Case no. E-92-0575), 1987-1993
Series III, Organizational Files, 1977-2002
Subseries A: United Women Firefighters, 1977-2002
Subseries B: Women in Fire Suppression/Fire Service, 1983-1999
Series IV, Photographs and Memorabilia, circa 1980-1999
Series V, Unprocessed Materials, 1957-2011
Berkman, Brenda; New York (N.Y.). Fire Dept.; United Women Firefighters.; Women in Fire Suppression (Organization).; Women in the Fire Service (Organization).; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Fire fighters |x Labor unions |z New York (State) |z New York.; Legal documents.; Manuscripts (document genre); Minutes.; New York (N.Y.); Photographs.; Sex discrimination against women |z New York (State) |z New York.; Sex discrimination in employment |z New York (State) |z New York.; Slides (photographs); Videotapes.; Women fire fighters |z New York (State) |z New York.; Women in the civil service |z New York (State) |z New York.; Women |z New York (State) |z New York |x Societies, etc.; Women's rights |z New York (State) |z New York.
- Series I: Brenda Berkman Papers, 1977-2005
  Scope and Content Note
  Series includes biographical material on Brenda Berkman, clippings related to her career, correspondence from her legal practice, and materials from her scrapbooks, primarily dealing with the case, Berkman v. City of New York.
  - Biographical, 1984-2000 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Clippings, 1979-2005 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, Children, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Legal Practice, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbooks, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbooks, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbooks, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbooks, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Scrapbooks, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Scrapbooks, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Scrapbooks, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Scrapbooks, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Series II: Legal Files, 1979-1993
  The series consists of legal documents and subject files from court cases brought by Brenda Berkman against the City of New York and the New York City Fire Department between 1977 and 1993, and from an unsuccessful appeal by the City of New York to Judge Charles Sifton's 1982 ruling that the City had discriminated against women through its physical exam. Includes materials from the following cases: Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case No. 79, C 1813), Class Action Suit (Berkman v. City of New York), 1977-1990; Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case no. 82-7654), Appeal, 1982 (Berkman v. City of New York, Appeal); and Brenda Berkman v. New York City Fire Department, Carlos Rivera, and Selig Ginsberg (Case no. E-92-0575), 1991-1993 (Berkman v. NYCFD).
  - Subseries A: Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case No. 79, C 1813), Class Action Suit, Legal Documents, 1979-1986
    Arrangement
    Materials are arranged chronologically and by suit.
    Subseries is comprised of legal documents (defendants' papers, exhibits, plaintiff's papers, and testimony), relating to the court case Berkman v. City of New York. This material covers not only the original case, but seven subsequent suits related to the dismissal and reinstatement with back-pay of firefighters Brenda Berkman and Zaida Gonzalez in 1983, the harassment cases of firefighters Katrina Cannon and Ella McNair, and the revised physical exam, 1162.
    - Berkman v. New York, Complaint, Class Action Suit (decided Mar 4, 1982, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Berkman v. New York, Depositions, Berkman (decided Mar 4, 1982), 1979 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Mar 4, 1982) I, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Mar 4, 1982) II, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Mar 4, 1982) I, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Mar 4, 1982) II, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Berkman v. New York, Memorandum, Decision, & Order (decided Mar 4, 1982) (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Berkman v. New York, Defendant's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) I (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Berkman v. New York, Defendant's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) II (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Berkman v. New York, Defendant's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) III (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Berkman v. New York, Defendant's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) IV (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Berkman v. New York, Memorandum and Order (decided Dec 8, 1983) (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) I (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) II (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) III (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) IV (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) V (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) VI (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) VII (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) VIII (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Dec 8, 1983) IX (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Dec 8, 1983) I (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Dec 8, 1983) II (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Dec 8, 1983) III (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Dec 8, 1983) IV (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Dec 8, 1983) V (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Dec 8, 1983) VI (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Dec 8, 1983) VII (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided May 13, 1986) I, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided May 13, 1986), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Nov 6, 1986), 1984 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Oct 24, 1986) I, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Oct 24, 1986) II, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Oct 8, 1985) I (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Oct 8, 1985) II (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Oct 8, 1985) III (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided May 13, 1986) I, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided May 13, 1986) II, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Oct 8, 1985) I (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Oct 8, 1985) II (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Oct 8, 1985) III (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Oct 8, 1985) IV (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Berkman v. New York, Testimony (decided Oct 8, 1985) V (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Feb 17, 1987), 1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided May 13, 1986) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Berkman v. New York, Defendant's Papers (decided Feb 17, 1987) I, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Berkman v. New York, Defendant's Papers (decided Feb 17, 1987) II, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Berkman v. New York, Defendant's Papers (decided Feb 17, 1987), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Berkman v. New York, Order (decided Feb 17, 1987), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Feb 17, 1987) I, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Feb 17, 1987) II, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Berkman v. New York, Plaintiff's Papers (decided Feb 17, 1987) III, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case No. 79, C 1813), Class Action Suit, Subject Files, 1979-1990
    Subseries is comprised of subject files (clippings, correspondence, notes and research) relating to the court case Berkman v. City of New York. This material covers not only the original case, but seven subsequent suits related to the dismissal and reinstatement with back-pay of firefighters Brenda Berkman and Zaida Gonzalez in 1983, the harassment cases of firefighters Katrina Cannon and Ella McNair, and the revised physical exam, 1162.
    - Berkman v. New York, Cannon, Katrina (I), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Berkman v. New York, Cannon, Katrina (II), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Berkman v. New York, Cannon, Katrina (III), 1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Berkman v. New York, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Berkman v. New York, McNair, Ella, 1986-1989 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Berkman v. New York, Notes and Research, [1979-1987] (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Subseries C: Brenda Berkman et al. v. City of New York et al. (Case no. 82-7654), Appeal, 1982
    Subseries consists of legal documents related to the unsuccessful appeal by the City of New York to Judge Sifton's 1982 ruling in Berkman v. City of New York.
    - Berkman v. New York, Appeal, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Berkman v. New York, Appeal, Exhibits: Transcriptions of Tapes, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Subseries D: Brenda Berkman v. New York City Fire Department, Carlos Rivera, and Selig Ginsberg (Case no. E-92-0575), 1987-1993
    Subseries consists of subject files, and includes correspondence, clippings, court papers, medical records, and press conference materials concerning Berkman's 1992 sexual harassment suit (Berkman v. NYCFD) against the New York City Fire Department, Fire Commissioner Carlos Rivera, and departmental physician, Dr. Selig Ginsberg.
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Chronology, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Clippings, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Correspondence, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Correspondence, Jan 1992-Mar 1992 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Correspondence, Apr 1992-Jun 1992 (Box 4, Folder 25)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Correspondence, Jul 1992-Sep 1992 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Correspondence, Oct 1992-Dec 1992 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Correspondence, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 28)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Demonstration, Women's Action Coalition, City Hall, Sep 10, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., FDNY Policies, 1987-1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Legal Papers, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Medical, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Notes and Research, 1992-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Press Conference, City Council, City Hall, Apr 23, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Press Conference, National Organization of Women (NOW), May 29, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Press Conference, City Council, City Hall, Jul 19, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Berkman v. NYCFD, et al., Press Releases, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Series III: Organizational Files, 1977-2002
  Series consists of organizational files of the United Women Firefighters (UFW) from 1977-2002, and of Women in Fire Service (WFS), alternately known as Women in Fire Suppression, from 1983-1995.
  - Subseries A: United Women Firefighters, 1977-2002
    Subseries includes materials related to the founding and operation of the UWF, such as clippings, correspondence, organizational materials, press conferences, the physical exam, membership, the FDNY's Special Advisory Committee on Women, and materials related to the training course at John Jay College of Criminal Justice-CUNY.
    - Center for Women in Government, Women in Uniformed Services, 1983-1985 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Clippings, 1977 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Clippings, 1978 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Clippings, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Clippings, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Clippings, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Clippings, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Clippings, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Clippings, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Clippings, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Clippings, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Clippings, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Clippings, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Clippings, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Clippings, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Clippings, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Clippings, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Clippings, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Clippings, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Clippings, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Clippings, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Columbia University: Survey, "Women in the FDNY" and Report, "Gender Integration in the Fire Department of the City of New York", 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Conference, "Women Tell the Truth", Apr 25, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Congress, Committee on Education and Labor Hearings, Mar 5, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Constitution and By-Laws, undated (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1983 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, Jan 1984-Jun 1984 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, Jul 1984-Dec 1984 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence, Jan 1987-Jun 1987 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence, Jul 1987-Dec 1987 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, Jan 1991-Jun 1991 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, Jul 1991-Dec 1991 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Council of the City of New York, Committee on Women, 1986-1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - FDNY, Physical Exam, Landy-Jacobs Contract, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - FDNY, Physical Exam, Research, 1983-1984 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - FDNY, Recruitment and Training Program, 1994-2000 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - FDNY, Recruitment and Training Program, Exam Prep Materials, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - FDNY, Sexual Harrassment, Training and Regulations, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - FDNY, Sexual Harrassment, Training and Regulations, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - FDNY, Sexual Harrassment, Training and Regulations, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - FDNY, Special Advisory Committee on Women, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - FDNY, Special Advisory Committee on Women, 1993-1999 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - History, 1989-1993 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Membership, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Newsletter, photocopy of handwritten original, signed Patricia Fitzgerald, [1983] (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - New York Fire Museum, Exhibit, "Fireworks: a Celebration of FDNY Civilian and Uniformed Women, 1865-1991," May 22-Sep 25, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Organizations: Police and Fire Departments, 1982-1985 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Subseries B: Women in Fire Suppression/Fire Service, 1983-1999